Guide to the Communications Workers of America Records WAG.124
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series XII: Reports and Studies, 1958-1981
  - Humphrey - Hawkins "Full Employment" Bill, 1977 (Box 352, Folder 37)
  - Free-Trade & the High Cost to the Nation: "Invasion, U.S.A.", 1978 (Box 352, Folder 38)
  - "Our Jobs, Our Future: Questions for the Candidate about America's Industry", 1980s (Box 352, Folder 39)
  - Consumers United for Rail Equity (CURE) Bulletin, Nov 1984 (Box 352, Folder 40)
  - Labor Research Assoc. Honors Con. Charles A. Hayes: A Trade Union Leader in Congress, undated (Box 352, Folder 41)
  - Facts on PACs: "Political Action Committee: American Campaign Finance", 1984 (Box 352, Folder 42)
  - Joint Center for Political Studies: Annual Report, 1984 (Box 352, Folder 43)
  - Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute, 1984-1985 (Box 352, Folder 44)
  - Robert Hitlin Research Assoc.: "Guide to Surveys & Polls", Jun 14, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 45)
  - "Politics and Markets" Monthly Newsletters, Feb 28, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 46)
  - Call to Congressional Quarterly's Seminar "Understanding Congress" Win/Spr 1985 (Box 352, Folder 47)
  - The Baron Report Newsletter: Copyrighted Material on Amer. Politics, 1984, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 48)
  - Citizens for Tax Justice Reports: "The Failure of Corporate Tax Incentives", 1985 (Box 352, Folder 49)
  - Duke University Institute of Policy Services and Public Affairs: "A Statement of Purpose for Political Parties", 1985 (Box 352, Folder 50)
  - The American Political Report, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 51)
  - Political Affairs: CPUSA Decline of Reaganism, Aug 1985 (Box 352, Folder 52)
  - Democratic Socialists of America: Correspondence, Aug 1985 (Box 352, Folder 53)
  - Political Campaign Institute: Brochures, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 54)
  - Democratic National Committee/CWA: Correspondence, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 55)
  - Democratic National Committee: PAC Reports, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 56)
  - Campaign for Congress Individuals, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 57)
  - Legislative Reports & Updates: Various Congresspersons & Caucuses, 1985-1986 (Box 352, Folder 58)
  - American for Democratic Action (ADA): Legislative Material, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 59)
  - CATO Institute Call to Conference "Reassessing the Political Spectrum", 1985 (Box 352, Folder 60)
  - The American Political Report (Newsletter), Jun 1985 (Box 352, Folder 61)
  - Politics, People and Issues (PPI Report), May 20, 1985 (Box 352, Folder 62)
  - AFL-CIO Legislative Dept. Booklet: "The People's Lobby: An AFL-CIO Report on the 98th Congress", 1985 (Box 352, Folder 63)
  - Directory of the U.S. Sen. and House of Rep.'s 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box 352, Folder 64)
  - CWA Correspondence; AFL-CIO, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings, 1st Constitutional Convention, Dec 1985 (Box 353, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1973 (Box 353, Folder 3)
  - Comm. Services Dept.: "How to Organize a Strike Assistance Program: Beyond the Picket Line", Dec 1974 (Box 353, Folder 4)
  - Political Material, 1966-1979 (Box 353, Folder 5)
  - Dept. of Professional Employees: Report, 1981 (Box 353, Folder 6)
  - Labor History Centennial Material, 1981 (Box 353, Folder 7)
  - Workers' Institute for Safety & Health, 1980's (Box 353, Folder 8)
  - Building & Construction Trades Dept.: Press Kit (2 copies), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 9)
  - "Bargaining Trends: Gains in 1984 Prospects for 1985" (Box 353, Folder 10)
  - Education Dept.; Education Update: Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Evolution of Work Pamphlet: "The Changing Situation of Workers & Their Unions", 1985 (Box 353, Folder 12)
  - Dept. of Econ. Research Housing & Credit Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 13)
  - Human Resource Dev. Institute, Apr 1985 (Box 353, Folder 14)
  - Labor Institute of Public Affairs: Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 15)
  - Right to Work & Plant Location and Business Climate Studies, Jul 1985 (Box 353, Folder 16)
  - Union Label & Service Trades Dept.: Proceedings of 61st Convention, 1983 (Box 353, Folder 17)
  - Union Label & Service Trades Dept.: Newsletter, Jan 12, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 18)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Political Pamphlets, 1966-1967 (Box 353, Folder 19)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Labor&Investments Newsletter, Dec 1984-Nov 1985, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 20)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Newsletter, Jan 1985-Sep 1985 (Box 353, Folder 21)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Resolution, Jun 1985 (Box 353, Folder 22)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Coordinated Bargaining Quarterly (CBQ), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 23)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: News Release on Trade, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 24)
  - Industrial Union Dept.: Trade Crisis Time for Action, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 25)
  - Dept. For Professional Employees Interface: Newsletter; Brochures, 1984-1985 (Box 353, Folder 26)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development; George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 27)
  - AIFLD: Report (In Spanish), May 9, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 28)
  - Labor Council for Latin American Advancement (LA Voz Latina), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 29)
  - AIFLD Report: Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 30)
  - North Amer. Congress on Latin America: "Report on the Americas", Nov 1985Dec 1985 (Box 353, Folder 31)
  - AAFLI (Asian-American Free Labor Institute) News: Monthly Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 32)
  - National Conference of Christians & Jews Annual Reports, 1983 (Box 353, Folder 33)
  - City of Hope, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 34)
  - National Education Assoc. Newsletter NEA Now, Jan 14, 1985-Jul 15, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 35)
  - National Planning Assoc. (Various Publications & Reports), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 36)
  - Histradut Public.'s (General Federation of Labor in Israel International Dept.), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 37)
  - Jewish Labor Committee Review: Newsletter, Dec 1985 (Box 353, Folder 38)
  - Hebrew Union College; Jewish Institute of Religion, Jan 1985 (Box 353, Folder 39)
  - Southerners for Economic Justice: "Fair Measure": Newsletter Winter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 40)
  - Publications: MPC News, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 41)
  - Maritime Newsletter: Voice of the AFL-CIO Maritime Trades Dept., 1985 (Box 353, Folder 42)
  - AFL-CIO Maritime Trades Dept; Minutes of the Exec. Bd. Mtg., 1985 (Box 353, Folder 43)
  - Summary of labor Arbit - Ration Awards; Report #316, Jul 15, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 44)
  - "Free Trade" Policy: Brochures/Pamphlets, 1983 (Box 353, Folder 45)
  - The Interdependent: Newsletter, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 46)
  - The Jobs Challenge: 'Pressures & Possibilities: Report of Jobs Panel', Apr 1985 (Box 353, Folder 47)
  - Status Report on the Situation in Africa, Nov 1985 (Box 353, Folder 48)
  - UN's 2nd World Conference to Combat Racism & Racial Discrimination Aug 1983, undated (Box 353, Folder 49)
  - Foreign News in the Media: Unesco Report (No 93), 1985 (Box 353, Folder 50)
  - Materials on the Holocaust, 1979, 1984-1985 (Box 353, Folder 51)
  - International Confed of Free Trade Unions: Publications, 1985 (Box 353, Folder 52)
  - Karen Silkwood; Union Sister: Special Report, 1970's (Box 353, Folder 53)
  - Women's Publications, 1980's (Box 353, Folder 54)
  - Ohio Bell Telephone Co.; Ohio Bell Newsletter, 1953, 1955, 1957 (Box 354, Folder 1)
  - Pacific Telephone Southern Counties Area: Tele-Digest Newsletter, 1972 (Box 354, Folder 2)
  - Mountain Bell Co.for MB Colorado Employees; MBToday Newsletter, Aug 1980 (Box 354, Folder 3)
  - Western Electric Co: Atlanta Works: UP Front Newsletter, 1983, 1984, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern Bell; NWB News, Newsletter, May 14, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Northwest Bell.; PNB News, Newsletter, undated, ca.1984 (Box 354, Folder 6)
  - General Tel. Co. Of California: California News, Newsletter, 1984, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 7)
  - AT&T Communications; Southern Exchange, Newsletter, Jul 31, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 8)
  - New England Tel. Co.; Rhode Island Review, Newsletter, Oct 1984 (Box 354, Folder 9)
  - New England Telephone Co.; This Week, Newsletter, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 10)
  - New England Tel. Co.; Green Mountaineer, Newsletter, Sep 1984, Dec 1984 (Box 354, Folder 11)
  - New England Tel. Co.; Baystater, Newsletter, Jul 1984, Sep 1984 (Box 354, Folder 12)
  - New York Tel.; The Exchange, Nov 1984-Dec 1985, Mar 1985, Jun 1985 (Box 354, Folder 13)
  - Mountain Bell Co.; MB Times, Newsletter, Feb 1985 (Box 354, Folder 14)
  - AT&T Information Systems.; Challenge, Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box 354, Folder 15)
  - AT&T Communications; Central Region Communicator, Newsletter, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 16)
  - AT&T Public Relations & Employee Information Dept.; Outlook, Newsletter, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 17)
  - AT&T Technologies.; Management Focus, Newsletter, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 18)
  - Bell Operating Cos.; BOC Week, Newsletter, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 19)
  - The Oregon & Washington Industrialist. Mag., Jul 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 354, Folder 20)
  - Michigan Bell Tel. Co.; Michigan Bell, Mag., Feb 1951 (Box 354, Folder 21)
  - New Jersey Bell; From Installer to Soldier, Mag., 1966 (Box 354, Folder 22)
  - Bell Telephone Magazine No.1-, Jun 4, 1905 (Box 354, Folder 23)
  - AT&T Information Systems.; Impact, Mag., 1983 (Box 354, Folder 24)
  - AT&T Communications.; Quest, Mag., 1984 (Box 354, Folder 25)
  - New England Telephone; New England Topics, Mag., Jul 1984-Dec 1984 (Box 354, Folder 26)
  - AT&T-Long Lines Dept.: Conflict & Compromise, Mag., Jun 1985-Jul 1985 (Box 354, Folder 27)
  - AT&T Company Codes of Conduct - Long Lines Dept., 1960's (Box 354, Folder 28)
  - AT&T Long Lines; Help Plan Your Future...through Skill Identification, 1977 (Box 354, Folder 29)
  - AT&T Political Action Reports, 1983 (Box 354, Folder 30)
  - Southern Bell - MIB - Management Information Bulletin, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 31)
  - Mountain Bell Reckoning With Competitive Realities, Jun 25, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 32)
  - Bell Atlantic Brochure re: N.J. Bell, 1984 (Box 354, Folder 33)
  - AT&T Human Resources Dept., 1977 (Box 354, Folder 34)
  - Northern Business Information, Inc.; The Telecom Strategy Letter, 1984, 1985 (Box 354, Folder 35)
  - CWA Constitution, 1953 (Box 355, Folder 1)
  - CWA Constitution, 1964 (Box 355, Folder 2)
  - CWA Constitution, 1965 (Box 355, Folder 3)
  - CWA Constitution, 1966 (Box 355, Folder 4)
  - CWA Constitution, 1971 (Box 355, Folder 5)
  - CWA Constitution, 1974 (Box 355, Folder 6)
  - CWA Constitution, 1975 (Box 355, Folder 7)
  - CWA Constitution, 1976 (Box 355, Folder 8)
  - CWA Constitution, 1977 (Box 355, Folder 9)
  - CWA Constitution, 1979 (Box 355, Folder 10)
  - CWA Constitution, 1980 (Box 355, Folder 11)
  - CWA Constitution, 1981 (Box 355, Folder 12)
  - CWA Constitution, 1982 (Box 355, Folder 13)
  - CWA Constitution, Mar 1983 (Box 355, Folder 14)
  - CWA Constitution, Jun 1983 (Box 355, Folder 15)
  - CWA Constitution, 1984 (Box 355, Folder 16)
  - CWA Constitution, 1985 (Box 355, Folder 17)
  - CWA Constitution (Not Bound), Jan 1978 (Box 355, Folder 18)
  - CWA Constitution (Not Bound), 1987 (Box 355, Folder 19)
  - CWA Local No. 2590 By-Laws, 1961 (Box 355, Folder 20)
  - Administration: CWA Historical Material in Archives, 1933-1957 (Box 356, Folder 1)
  - Administration: Retention of Records in CWA Headquarters Office, 1964 (Box 356, Folder 2)
  - Administration: Joseph A. Beirne Corr. Files and Location of Other Joseph A. Beirne Files, 1964-1969 (Box 356, Folder 3)
  - Administration: Joseph A. Beirne Corr. Microfilmed in 1968, 1964-1975 (Box 356, Folder 4)
  - Records of Joseph A. Beirne, Turned over to Anne Beirne or Pres. Glenn E. Watts, 1964-1977 (Box 356, Folder 5)
  - Oral History Project; University of Iowa Report on Process and Prospects, 1969-1971 (Box 356, Folder 6)
  - Administration (Beirne): 1st, 1969-1974 (Box 356, Folder 7)
  - Administration (Beirne): 2nd, 1969-1974 (Box 356, Folder 8)
  - Administration (Beirne): 3rd, 1969-1974 (Box 356, Folder 9)
  - CWA IndEX to Filing Proceedings: URE (revised), Jul 16, 1971 (Box 356, Folder 10)
  - CWA Enhancement of CWA and Postage Stamp for CWA, Beirne, 1971-1972 (Box 356, Folder 11)
  - CWA Revised Filing Procedure, Aug 6, 1973 (Box 356, Folder 12)
  - CWA IndEX to Filing Procedure: URE; Revised, Jun 2, 1972 (Box 356, Folder 13)
  - CWA IndEX to Filing Procedure: URE; Revised, Jan 31, 1973 (Box 356, Folder 14)
  - Filing Procedure, Revised, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 15)
  - CWA File IndEX: Replacement Sheets for File Index Issued, Jan 11, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 16)
  - Central File Index; CWA Index to Filing Procedure: URE, Revised, Jan 11, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 17)
  - Central File Index; CWA Index to Filing Procedure: URE, Revised, Jul 26, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 18)
  - Central File Index; CWA Index to Filing Procedure: URE, Revised, Nov 1974 (Box 356, Folder 19)
  - Numerical and Alphabetical File IndEX (1), 1976 (Box 356, Folder 20)
  - Numerical and Alphabetical File IndEX (2), 1976 (Box 356, Folder 21)
  - Numerical and Alphabetical List to File Index: 1st, 1976 (Box 356, Folder 22)
  - Numerical and Alphabetical List to File Index:2nd, 1976 (Box 356, Folder 23)
  - Files of Joseph A. Beirne (See File #1- Binders), 1976 (Box 356, Folder 24)
  - Contents of Files of the Late President Emeritus, 1938-1975, 1976-1977 (Box 356, Folder 25)
  - CENTRAL FILE IndEX: 1, 1987 (Box 356, Folder 26)
  - CENTRAL FILE IndEX: 2, 1987 (Box 356, Folder 27)
  - CWA TAPE IndEX: Tape Library; Conventions, Executive Board, Headquarters' Meetings, undated (Box 356, Folder 28)
  - CWA TAPE IndEX: Tape Library; Conventions, Executive Board, Headquarters' Meetings, undated (Box 356, Folder 29)
  - A New History of the CWA Manuscript by Thomas R. Brooks, 1975 (Box 357)
- Series XIII: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 13 websites in 13 archived websites.
  https://cwa-union.org/ is made up of the CWA newsletter, blog, event listings, press releases, issues and action alerts, and other multimedia. Speed Matters is a project of the CWA to advocate for affordable, high speed internet for universal internet access for all Americans. The website contains the project's principles, benefits to expanded access to high speed internet, publications produced by the project, news, and other organizational partnerships. CWA Political is the website for the CWA Committee on Political Education – Political Contributions Committee. The website contains information on the CWA political action fund, polical activist training materials, listing of endorsed candidates, resources, and their newsletter, CWA Collective Briefing.
  StoptheTPP is a project organized by the Communications Workers of America to raise public awareness of and organize opposition to the Trans Pacific Partnership on the grounds that the massive trade deal would lead to deregulation that could have negative impacts for workers as well as consumers. The site features fact sheets and educational resources that detail the effects of the TPP across different industries like commercial fishing and pharmaceuticals, news related to ongoing developments, and information about how to get involved in opposition to the deal. As the United States was pulled out of the TPP in 2017, the site is no longer actively updated. T-Mobile Sprint Facts is a project organized by the Communication Workers of America to raise public awareness of and organize opposition to the merger between mobile service providers T-Mobile and Sprint on the grounds that the merger is not in the public interest, that it would result in the loss of retail and communications jobs, that both companies have a history of violating labor and employment laws, and that the proposed benefits (like increased rural coverage) are exaggerated. The site features fact sheets on the impact of the merger in different states and for rural communities, news about ongoing developments, links documents like letters of oppositions by US lawmakers and documentation of regulatory hearings, and a form by which site users can file a public comment opposing the merger.
  The CWA Steward Strong Web Portal provides training materials and resources for CWA stewards. It includes PDFs of the Steward Resource Manual, the Steward Participant Workbook, organizing and mobilizing resources, materials for worksite bulletin board, grievance handling resources, being a steward in a workplace without a contract training manual, and a stewards glossary.
  Fair 5G is a project of the Communications Workers of America that provides resources for the deployment of wireless networks that supports digital equity, workers' rights and community benefits. It includes news and reports analyzing public-private partnerships on implementing 5G in US cities, the wireless resiliency cooperative framework, small cell deployment, and digital equity.
  Build Broadband Better is an online petition created by the Communications Workers of America to support the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to grant states and communities across the United States to build and improve their broadband networks.
  The Congressional Vote Scorecard website ranks how current and former United States Congress members voted on key bills important to the CWA. Vote results date back to 2019. The website particularly covers the Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act.
  Campaign to Organize Digital Employees (CODE-CWA) is an organizing campaign launched by the Communications Workers of America to organize workers in tech, software, video game, and digital industries. CWA successfully organized workers at Glitch, Voltage Entertainment, Blue State, Alphabet, Mobilize, NPR Digital Media, Catalist, Change.org, New York Times Tech, EveryAction, Paizo, Vodeo Games, Raven Software QA, Image Comics, AppFolio, Seven Seas Entertainment, Blizzard Albany QA, The Atlantic Business & Tech departments, Tender Claws, and Meow Wolf. The website contains news from organizing efforts, training resources, and a listing of organizing success stories.
  The Communications Workers of America Public, Healthcare and Education Workers (PHEW) sector represents social workers, educators, health care providers, computer programmers, heavy equipment operators, and corrections and police officers. The website contains local news from the sectors, conference information, and COVID-19 activism and resources.
  Save the News is an action campaign from the Communications Workers of America to promote the Local Journalism Sustainability Act to save local journalism jobs. The website highlights the impact on the loss of local journalists and reporting on news deserts and journalism job cuts.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly and semiannually.
  In 2020, https://cwa-union.org/ was increased to biweekly. In 2021 it was shifted to monthly crawls.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of cwa-union.org, cwa.org, speedmatters.org, tmobilesprintfacts.org, stopthetpp.org, fair5g.org, cwa-phew.org, buildbroadbandbetter.org, and cwapolitical.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints. Crawl was also expanded to include files.cwa-union.org and unionhall.cwalocals.org.